Get rid of it.
把牠丟掉
What?
什麼？
What's the point of taking in a sickly dog?
收留這種虛弱的病狗有什麼意義？
As my daughter, you have a responsibility to rise above your peers.
身為我的女兒，妳有責任出類拔萃
In order to do that, you must toss aside the weak.
為此，妳必須拋下弱小
Don't waste your time.
不要浪費時間
Only do what you need to succeed.
只做為求成功必要的事
Unless you want to end up on the street like that pathetic dog.
除非妳想跟那隻喪家之犬 一樣被拋棄，淪落街頭
Everyone!
各位！
Today, we're welcoming Tendo and his crew!
今天我們要歡迎天道一夥人
Let's go all out and celebrate!
大家一起出來慶祝吧
Cheers!
乾杯！
Drink up, everyone!
大家儘管喝
This is my way of showing how much I appreciate
我要藉此向每天
all the hard work you put into the company everyday!
為公司辛苦打拼的你們表達感謝
Do you think nailing a zombie would infect you?
你覺得跟殭屍搞過會被感染嗎？
Are you seriously after that zombie hipster chick?
你真的想上那個殭屍小妞？
What can I say. She's totally my type.
沒辦法，她完全就是我的菜
Hey newbie! Can't you see I need a refill?
菜鳥，你沒看到我要續杯嗎？
Coming!
馬上來
-Stop tripping everywhere, damn! -I'm sorry.
-喂，誰叫你跌倒的？ -抱歉
Pull yourself together!
給我振作點
-You're ruining the vibe! -Sorry.
-氣氛都被你毀了 -對不起
-Weren't you a working professional? -I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
-你真的有當過上班族嗎？
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
對不起…
-Eventually, I'll lead Japan! -I'll fill up your glass.
-我遲早會成為全日本的領導人 -我來替您斟酒
Idiot!
蠢蛋
I don't want some old bag's booze!
我不要喝老太婆的酒，噁心死了
I only accept drinks from young women.
只有年輕妹子能替我倒酒
Hey, you, over there.
那邊的女人
Pour me a drink.
給我過來倒酒
Here. Ditch the water and stop acting like you're too good for this.
來，你也別裝清高，只顧著喝水了
Drink up.
喝吧
Or are you saying you won't accept a drink from your boss?
還是說妳不願意喝上司倒的酒？
You swallow like a champ.
喝得很爽快嘛
There's something else I want you to swallow.
我想給妳嚐嚐別的東西
Try being friendlier.
親切一點嘛
Be nice or let me fondle your tits.
要不學會陪笑，不然就來讓我捏奶子
That's all women are good for anyway.
女人就只有這點用處而已
-Hey newbie, where are our orders? -Hey, Tendo. Booze.
-菜鳥，我們的菜呢？ -天道，來倒酒
I asked for fries too.
我也點了薯條
Hey, Tendo!
天道！
Yes! I'm sorry.
是，抱歉
-What did you want? -Booze. I'm out of booze.
-有什麼事？ -酒，我的酒喝完了
Yes! I'm sorry.
是，抱歉
Here you go.
請用
It's empty!
這是空的！
Why are you giving me an empty bottle?
你給我空酒瓶做什麼？
Who fixed your car, patched up your buddy, and let you sleep in a safe place?
是誰幫你修好車，幫你朋友包紮 還給你安全的地方睡覺？
All you need to do is shut up and do exactly what I tell you!
你只需要閉上嘴巴 乖乖聽我的話就好
I'm sorry. I'm sorry!
對不起…
I'll bring you a new one right away.
我馬上給您拿一瓶新的
Need to succeed…
必須要贏
Need to win…
必須要成功
And to do that, you need to obey me.
為此，妳必須乖乖聽我的話
Even before I could talk,
從我學會講話之前
my father kept telling me what I needed to do
我父親就不斷指使我該做什麼
so much that I thought my name was "Anita."
甚至讓我誤以為 自己的名字叫做「必須」
In his youth, my father went to the States alone,
我父親年輕時便隻身前往美國
and within his lifetime built a massive corporation.
窮極一生建立了超大型企業
He weathered the Lehman Brothers collapse
他熬過雷曼兄弟破產危機
to become a calculating and cold-blooded financier
成為一名精於算計的冷血金融家
that even the Americans feared.
連美國人都怕他
As his daughter…
身為他的女兒
perfection was always expected of me.
完美總是被視為理所當然
Sorry to hide you here.
抱歉，把你藏在這種地方
If Daddy finds you, he'll kick you out.
要是被爸爸發現，他會把你趕出去的
Is that all you can say?
你的叫聲就是這樣嗎？
Then I guess I'll name you Roo!
那麼我就叫你阿魯吧！
You're not hungry?
你不餓嗎？
Are you not feeling well?
是不是身體不舒服？
INTRO TO VETERINARY SCIENCE
（小型動物獸醫學入門）
Roo?
阿魯？
Are you better now?
你有精神了？
Thank…
真是…
Thank goodness.
太好了
I'm so… I'm so glad!
真的太好了
Oh, Roo!
阿魯
You want to become a doctor?
妳想當醫生？
There's a high risk of being sued, and they don't make a lot of money.
醫生容易惹上官司，又賺不了多少錢
What's the point?
有什麼意義？
Doctors and lawyers are to be used by people like us.
醫生和律師就是要供我們差遣的
You need to stand above them.
妳必須比那些人更優秀
-But-- -We're done talking.
-但是… -就這樣
Regarding your possession in the attic,
至於妳在閣樓裡的那玩意
I contacted the humane society and had them put it down.
我已經聯絡收容所 讓他們將牠處理掉了
What?
什麼？
Who do you have to thank for this life of luxury in this house?
妳能在這個家過著 不愁吃穿的生活，是拜誰之賜？
All you need to do is shut up and obey me.
妳“必須”閉上嘴巴 乖乖聽我的話就好
You need to finish what you've started.
做事“必須”要有始有終
You don't need to hang around with those who are less than you.
妳不該跟那些比妳差的人交朋友
There's no need to date that boy.
妳不該跟那個男孩約會
Marriage is a means for peers to reproduce.
婚姻的目的是 讓門當戶對的人家傳宗接代
-Need, need, need… -You're in a different class than him.
-必須這樣，必須那樣… -妳跟他是不同層次的人
Shut up already.
囉嗦死了
But if I don't obey him, I can't survive here.
但是不聽話就無法在這裡生存
I need to obey his every word.
我必須要聽從他的每一句話
Hey!
喂！
What do you think you're doing to my precious goods, idiot?!
你把我珍貴的貨物怎麼了？你這蠢貨
Looks like you'll need to work tomorrow and over the weekend to finish this!
看來你明天不能放假 要來加班才做得完這些了
-But you promised it would end today! -Hey!
-但是我們說好我只做到今天 -喂
You're a waste of my food!
你這個飯桶
Do you know how much loss I've incurred because of you?
你知道自己害我損失了多少東西嗎？
Of course you wouldn't know!
你當然不知道！
A slow, dim-witted, stupid, and lazy wimp like you generates loss just by living!
你這種慢吞吞，又傻又蠢的懶鬼 光活著都嫌浪費
Your breathing is a waste of company resources!
你光是呼吸都是社會的負擔
You could work here your entire life and it wouldn't be enough!
就算你在這裡工作一輩子也不夠賠
But you know what, Tendo?
但是我跟你說，天道
That's what I find so charming about you.
就是這樣所以我無法放著你不管
Chief?
部長？
The reason I'm so strict with you
我之所以對你這麼嚴格
is because I actually have confidence in your abilities.
是因為我對你的能力有信心
So, stay.
所以你就留下來吧
-But… -Think about it, Tendo.
-但是… -天道，你想想
What's driving you to go back out into a dangerous world like that?
你為什麼想回到那個危險的世界？
Freedom is tough.
自由是很辛苦的
You have to make every decision yourself.
你必須自己做出所有決定
What to eat, where to sleep, when to take a crap…
吃什麼、在哪裡睡覺 什麼時候上廁所
Try thinking about that all the time.
無時無刻都要想著這些
It's not easy.
不輕鬆啊
It will drive you off the rails.
那會把你逼瘋的
Tendo, I don't want you to end up that way.
天道，我不想要你落得那個下場
That's why I'll tell you what to do.
所以由我來告訴你該做什麼
Listen to me, and you won't need to think.
聽我的話，你就不必思考
I'm kinda jealous of the chance you're getting.
我還挺羨慕你有這種機會的
Put your wants aside.
別去思考你自己想要什麼
All you need to do is stay and follow my orders.
你只要留下來聽從我的命令就好
Shizuka, do you see all those poor people?
閑，妳看這些窮人
Those are people who have lived how they've wanted to.
那就是隨自己的慾望生活的結果
You're different from them.
妳跟他們不一樣
Put your wants aside.
放下妳的慾望
In order to win, follow my orders and do only what you need to do.
為了勝利 妳要聽從我的命令，只做該做的事
As my daughter, don't become an embarrassment.
身為我的女兒，不要讓我丟臉
Are you listening? I'm saying this for your benefit.
妳有沒有在聽？我這麼說是為了妳好
It's actually…
這實際上…
for your benefit, isn't it?
是為你自己好，不是嗎？
All right! I'm going to drink so much today!
很好，我今天要大喝特喝
You're not done until you've carried all of those out!
你要把這些全部搬下車才能下班
Okay!
好的
100 THINGS I WANT TO DO BEFORE BECOMING A ZOMBIE
（在成為殭屍前要做的100件事）
1. CONFESS TO THE GIRL I LOVED
（1：向喜歡的女生告白）
32. DRINK AND LAUGH WITH MY BEST BUD
（32：與摯友把酒言歡到天亮）
You're such…
你真是個…
36. BECOME A SUPERHERO
（36：成為超級英雄）
…a weird guy.
怪人
35. REMEMBER MY CHILDHOOD DREAM 36. BECOME A SUPERHERO
（35：想起兒時的夢想 36：成為超級英雄）
FRESH
（產地直送）
There!
好了
Amazing. What a great haul! We got a lot today!
太棒了，今天真是大豐收
Have you ever noticed that Kosugi
你有沒有發現小杉哥
never helps with any of the dangerous acquisition runs?
絕對不會親自參加 像這種危險的跑腿任務？
Idiot! Just be happy we don't get treated like the rest of the laborers!
別傻了！你該慶幸我們沒有 跟其他勞工一樣被剝削
Okay!
也是
Did you close the door?
門關好了嗎？
We don't want any zombies getting into the truck.
可不能讓殭屍溜到車上
I'm sorry!
抱歉啦
-Let's hurry up and pull out! -Okay!
-我們快點離開吧 -好
As promised, it's been two days.
已經過了兩天
As we agreed, we'll be getting out of here.
我們說好時間到了就離開
Sorry, Akira.
輝，真抱歉
You went through all that for me.
你為我吃了這麼多苦
But that ends today.
但是就到今天為止
Actually…
那個…
About that…
關於這點
I think I might stay
我想我還是留下來
and keep working for the chief.
繼續為部長工作好了
What are you talking about, Akira?
輝，你在說什麼？
It's just…
就是說…
It's dangerous out there.
外面很危險
And I'm not really cut out to survive it.
我絕對活不下去的
If I stay here, the chief said he will look after me.
如果留在這裡，部長說會照顧我
Hey, what the hell happened to you?
你是發生了什麼事？
Hey, Akira!
輝
Akira!
輝！
It seems Tendo really likes his job here!
看來天道很喜歡在這裡的工作呢
All right.
我知道了
In that case, we'll be leaving on our own.
這樣的話，我們就自己上路吧
Let's go, Kencho.
走吧，憲一
Hey, hold on!
等等
-There's no way we can do that! -Why not?
-我們不能這麼做 -為什麼不能？
He says he wants to stay, after all.
是他自己說想留下的
I mean, I need to repay the chief for everything he's done.
我必須報答部長對我的恩情
In order to do that, I need to keep working here.
所以我必須繼續在這裡工作
Need, need, need, need! Shut up already!
必須這樣，必須那樣，閉嘴啦！
Akira, seeing as how we won't meet again,
輝，既然我們不會再見面了
let me tell you one last thing.
我就告訴你最後一件事
That man who's trying to make you give yourself over to him completely…
那個想要你把一切奉獻給他的男人
Do you know what he's really after?
你知道他真正圖的是什麼嗎？
Well, he wants to dominate you, and make you do what he wants.
他想要征服你，好讓你任憑他擺布
Your free will, that's yours alone.
應該屬於你自己的自由意志
Your freedom to choose…
你的選擇自由
The self-respect you need to live…
你活下去所需要的尊嚴
Your soul!
你的靈魂
Your pride!
你的驕傲
He wants you to abandon them, so he can take them from you.
他都要你一一放棄，好全部奪走
He has no self-esteem, and he's never satisfied.
他對自己毫無自信，也永遠不會滿足
All he can do is put others down to make himself seem bigger.
他只懂得靠糟蹋其他人 來表現自己的優越
That sad man will do anything to assert himself
那個悲哀的男人會想盡辦法展現權力
and get a brief sense of fulfillment by demeaning you.
透過貶低你來取得短暫的成就感
Until today, I was just like you are now.
直到今天為止，我原本跟你一樣
But you were the one who finally opened my eyes!
但是你讓我看清了
I'm not handing myself over to anyone ever again!
我再也不會受任何人擺布了
Do you need to leave?
你必須走
Do you need to stay?
還是必須留下？
With the uncertain state our world is in,
活在這個連明天在哪都不知道的世界
no one can say what the right answer will be.
沒有人知道正確的答案
But at the very least, right now,
但是至少現在
I want to get away from this gross shithead
我一心一意只想盡快
as soon as possible with every fiber of my being!
遠離這個噁心的臭老頭
Honestly, this is why women are such trouble.
我就說吧，女人只會找麻煩
They immediately go into hysterics and there's no use talking to them.
總是突然歇斯底里 跟她們說什麼道理都沒用
Right, everyone?
大家說是不是？
Well, Akira? What will you do?
輝，所以你打算怎麼做？
You're not a machine or a zombie.
你不是機器，也不是殭屍
You're still human, aren't you?
你還是人，對吧？
What do you actually want to do?
你真正想要做的是什麼？
36. BECOME A SUPER HERO 37. TELL OFF MY JERK OF A BOSS
（36：成為超級英雄 37：對討厭的上司把話說清楚）
How long are you going to keep spouting nonsense?
妳還要繼續胡說八道多久？
Give me that!
給我
Who cares about what you want to do?!
誰在乎你想要做什麼？
You don't need this!
這什麼爛東西
1. CONFESS TO THE GIRL I LOVED
（一：向喜歡的女生告白）
What do you think you're doing, Tendo?
天道，你在做什麼？
Who gave you permission to…
是誰允許你…
Chief.
部長
Thank you for taking care of me.
謝謝你的照顧
But this is where we part ways.
但是我們就在這裡道別吧
I don't want anything to do with you.
我不想跟你扯上任何關係了
I never want to see you ever again!
我再也不想見到你了
But you still owe me.
但你還是欠我人情
I won't be able to make it up to you! Please accept my apologies!
我沒辦法補償你了，請接受我的道歉
That's irresponsible, don't you think?
你不覺得這樣太不負責了嗎？
My apologies!
真是抱歉
But I was good to you!
虧我對你這麼好！
You'll regret this!
你會後悔的
Trash like you will be zombie food the moment you step outside!
你這種垃圾 一踏出去就會被殭屍吃掉
Even so, that's fine, right?
就算是這樣也沒關係，對吧？
It's better than being worked like a zombie
總好過跟殭屍一樣被你壓榨
while not being able to do a single thing I want.
還不能做自己想做的事
37. TELL OFF MY JERK OF A BOSS
（37：對討厭的上司把話說清楚）
The supply gathering team is back!
補給組回來了
We pulled in a large haul today!
今天收穫滿滿呢
Check it out!
看好了
I bet you're going to be surprised…
你們一定會很意外…
Calm down! It's just one zombie!
冷靜點，只不過是一隻殭屍而已
-This is bad. -Just stay cool and…
-不好了 -保持冷靜…
-I have to get away! -Hey, wait!
-我得趕快離開 -等等
I don't want to die!
我不想死
Thank you.
謝謝
Thank you!
謝謝你
Kencho!
憲一！
Shizuka!
閑！
-We're okay! -No!
-我們沒事 -不要
Hey, over here! Hurry!
過來，快點
Damn it!
可惡
Damn it. We can't save them all!
可惡，我們救不了所有人
Stay back! Stay back!
走開…
Get away from me, you damn zombies!
別過來，你們這些該死的殭屍
Chief.
部長
The food truck…
行動餐車…
Hey, delivery team! I have an idea.
補給組的各位，我有個點子
Will you help?
可以請你們幫忙嗎？
I'm not built for running!
有代謝症候群的人不適合跑步啊
Tendo?
天道？
Chief! Now's our chance! Hurry and get over here! Hurry!
部長，趁現在，快點過來！
That Akira… Why is he helping that guy?
輝…他為什麼要救那個傢伙？
Akira!
輝！
I thought you didn't want anything to do with him?
你不是不想跟他扯上關係了嗎？
I don't,
我是不想
but standing by while someone's about to get eaten by zombies
但是眼睜睜看著別人被殭屍吃掉
isn't on my bucket list!
不在我的清單上啊
Now!
就是現在！
We're counting on you!
靠你了
All right!
好！
Now then…
現在…
Let's go!
我們走吧！
Go?
走？
-We're not going to jump from here, right? -One.
-我們不是要從這裡跳過去吧？ -一…
Two.
二…
Three!
三！
Akira!
輝！
You're amazing, Akira!
你太棒了，輝
Good job, newbie!
幹得好，菜鳥
That was amazing!
太厲害了
Thank you!
謝謝
I only pulled it off thanks to all of your help.
我能夠辦到，都是因為有你們幫忙
Don't be so modest!
別這麼謙虛啦
Shizuka!
閑！
We managed to pull through!
我們成功度過危機了
Good grief.
真是的
Honestly,
你實在太亂來了
you're always doing something crazy.
老是做這種瘋狂的事
-It wasn't that great. -I wasn't giving you a compliment.
-也沒那麼厲害啦 -我不是在稱讚你
As expected from my subordinate!
我的屬下果然不負重望
He was a fine example, wasn't he?
他真是個好榜樣，對不對？
You need to take after Tendo and, from now on, be more--
從現在起你們要多學學天道…
Sorry, Kosugi.
抱歉了，小杉哥
But I'm done working for you.
我不想替你工作了
You're always making people work while you do nothing!
你總是要別人工作 自己卻什麼都不做
You're a dictator.
你太專制了
That newbie was a better leader than you!
那個菜鳥當領袖比你優秀多了
We've more than paid our dues.
我想我們已經把欠你的份還清了
It's about time we leave.
我們該走了
Thanks so much.
謝謝各位
We brought this stuff in, so we're going to haul it out!
物資是我們帶過來的 所以我們要全部帶走
No, wait!
不，等等
Guys! Wait!
你們等等啊
-I treated you well, didn't I? -Let's go.
-我待你們不薄，不是嗎？ -走吧
Wait… Please! Hey!
等等，拜託你們
Please wait!
拜託你們別走啊！
You're joking, right?
你是在開玩笑吧？
You really don't remember?
真的都不記得了？
I don't.
我真是太丟臉了
I blanked out whenever the chief was around.
每次面對部長，我就腦筋一片空白
That said, working sucked! Maybe I'm not cut out for it!
話說回來，工作實在太辛苦了 也許我真的不適合
It feels like I'll never find the right job for me.
感覺我永遠也找不到合適的工作了
Is that so bad? There's no rush to find a job.
有什麼關係，何必急著找工作呢？
What?
什麼？
Online personalities, esports athletes, drone pilots…
網紅、電競選手、無人機飛行員…
New jobs are created all the time.
不斷有新的工作出現
Ones we couldn't imagine a hundred years ago…
那些都是一百年前無法想像的工作
We don't know what tomorrow will bring in this world.
我們在這個無法預知明天的世界中
Or what jobs there will be. It's anyone's guess.
將來會有些什麼工作，誰都說不準
So do what you want to do and enjoy doing it.
所以就做你想做的事，並樂在其中
Enjoy it for all it's worth.
好好享受就行了
Eventually, one day, one of those things may become a job that only you can do.
最後到了某天，搞不好那就成為 只有你能勝任的工作
You're right!
說得也是
KUROMATSU, GUNMA
（群馬縣）
Next time: Sushi & Hot Springs of the Dead.
下一集：死者的壽司與溫泉之旅